Manuel Lopez Anido

Engineer and Web Developer at Accenture



Name: Manuel Lopez Anido

Age: 29 years

• Nationality: Argentinian and Spanish

Location: Rosario, Argentina

• Telephone Number: +54 9 341 3240353

• **Email:** manuellopezanido@gmail.com

Portfolio:



manuellopezanido.com



PROFILE

Industrial Engineer and Software Developer with over 4 years of professional experience. Building, improving, and maintaining entire web applications for different large companies. As an industrial engineer, I am qualified to analyze, improve, automate and optimize the performance of processes and systems. I'm a very optimistic, curious, and responsible person who enjoys working in teams. I'm motivated by learning new knowledge, and I'm always striving to expand my professional skill set.



EDUCATION

Academic Degree: Industrial Engineer at Universidad Nacional de Rosario (UNR). (2014-2022).

Developer

Frontend: Typescript, React, Next.js, TanStack Query, Zustand, Tailwind CSS, Sass.

Backend: Node.js, Express, Nest.js, MongoDB, SQL, Zod.

Version control: Git, GitHub.

Others: Visual Basic for Application, MatLab, Blockchains knowledge

Languages:

Spanish: Native Speaker

<u>English</u>: Fluent Speaker. TOEFL iBT, Cambridge First Certificate in English. <u>German</u>: Basic. 3 years studying at Universidad Nacional de Rosario



EXPERIENCES

Senior Web Development Engineer at Accenture. (Dec 2022 - Present):

Currently assigned to "Banco Galicia", the most important Accenture client in

Argentina. Working in an Agile Team, responsible for building and maintaining critical web applications that support the bank's day-to-day operations.

Developing the frontend using Next.js and the backend using Nest.js, following the microservice architecture.

Engineer at Liliana Electrodomesticos company. (Jun 2021 – Dec 2022):

Developer in charge of designing, building, updating, improving, and maintaining a web application created from scratch. Both frontend and backend. An application that is used by hundreds of workers every day, in different areas of the company. Mentoring and supervising two junior internship developers who collaborate with the app.

Automating and improving complex processes and data management for the company, programming in Visual Basics for Applications.

Intern for the Municipality of Rosario. (Mar 2019 - Oct 2020)

Intern at the engineering consulting company "Goldvarg Ingeniería". (Nov 2017 - Mar 2018)

Volunteer in the non-governmental organization "TECHO". (Mar 2018 - Present)

Personal training experience living six months in the United States. (Jan - Jul 2012)